ALEKSANDR FEDCHENKO

PROFILE

I'm 30 years old. I have an experience in web application design (microsevice, serverless and monolithic architectures), back-end and embedded software development, DevOps and system administration. I carried out researches in the field of control theory (satellite power supplies and UAV) and published multiple articles and patents. I have good communication skills and held several senior positions. Currently I'm interested in highload and ML projects that can give me an opportunity to acquire new professional competencies and to work with talented people.

EXPERIENCE

B2Basket.ru

Moscow, RU

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep 2019 - Nov 2020

- Design of E-commerce marketplace integration platform
- Cloud infrastructure deployment and service administration
- Development of marketplace and pricing platform modules
- Research activity (ML-algorithms for data matching services)
- IT department planning and management









Python Go FastAPI PyTorch PostgreSQL Mongo RabbitMQ Kubernetes Terraform Linux











NPP Strela (НПП Стрела)

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Zhukovsky, RU

Feb 2018 - Sep 2019

- Development of UAV diagnostics software and real-time operating system
- Design of ground control station software
- UAV mathematical model derivation and digital filters calculation
- Research and synthesis of control systems (H∞ and adaptive ML controllers)
- Development department management















Autonomous Energetics (Автономная Энергетика)

Krasnovarsk, RU Feb 2011 - Feb 2018

RESEARCH ENGINEER

· Design of electronic load embedded software

- Development of power supply test stand interface
- Research activity (charge-discharge devices for spacecraft battery testing)
- Analysis and synthesis of control systems for switched-mode power supplies
- Circuit design and test stand assembling





Python C++ pandas Django SQLite Qt Linux FreeRTOS Altium



EDUCATION

MSc in Electrical Engineering (Motion Control Systems and Navigation) Reshetnev Siberian State University of Science and Technology Sep 2015 - Jul 2017

Specialist Degree in Electrical Engineering (Aircraft Control Systems) Siberian State Aerospace University Sep 2008 - Jul 2014



+7 929 335 61 48

alek.fedchenko@gmail.com

@alekfed

alekfed.com

Moscow, RU

Emacs

SKILLS ====

Languages: Python, Go, JS/TS, SQL, Bash, C++, Common Lisp Frameworks: Django, FastAPI, Fiber, Apollo, Flask, Keras, React DB & MQ: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ DevOps: Kubernetes, Helm, Nix, GitLab CI, Ansible, Terraform Other: LaTeX, Inkscape, KiCad,

LANGUAGES =

Russian Native English C1 Japanese N5

PATENTS —

RU153595U1 RU154432U1 RU153595U1

INTERESTS

Movies Mathematics Music Cooking Design Tennis